                <ceilings>The Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative offers grants of up to $1,800 for increasing home insulation in attics, cathedral ceilings and flat roofs. The amount you are eligible for will depend on factors such as what insulation is currently in your home, how much insulation you add and the type of attic/ceiling your home has. Insulation slows the rate of heat loss, resulting in improved energy use and reduced energy costs. Installing insulation in an attic, cathedral ceiling or flat roof is eligible for a grant, as long as minimum levels of insulation and coverage are achieved. If your house consists of more than one roof or roof type, the grant amount will be pro-rated and calculated based on roof type and area. It is recommended that you take work-in-progress photos to document retrofits that cannot be visually verified by the energy advisor, such as insulation in a cathedral ceiling.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A; The insulation in your attic was assessed at R-__. Because the amount of insulation in your attic has been assessed as greater than R-12 but less than or equal to R25,  a grant of up to $1800 is available for adding insulation to reach R-50 or more.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;Keeping the heat in - section 5 has valuable information that could be of interest to you: https://www.nrcan.gc.ca/energy-efficiency/homes/make-your-home-more-energy-efficient/keeping-the-heat/chapter-5-roofs-and-attics/15637 </ceilings>
                <exposedFloors>Through the Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative, a grant of $350 is available for adding insulation to exposed floors. The exposed floor area must be a minimum of 11 square meters (120 square feet) and may be composed of either one large exposed floor area or multiple smaller areas. Each section of exposed floor area must be entirely insulated with a minimum additional insulation level of RSI 3.52 (R-20). Insulating exposed floors may result in energy savings and improve comfort in rooms above exposed floors. It is recommended that you take work-in-progress photos to document retrofits that cannot be visually verified by the energy advisor, such as insulation covered by drywall.</exposedFloors>
                <foundation>The Canada Greener Homes Initiative offers grants of up to $1,500 for adding insulation to basement walls. Insulating basement walls can reduce energy costs and improve comfort. Grants are based on the RSI/R-value of the added insulation and the percentage of wall area insulated. The current amount of insulation does not affect the grant amounts. A minimum of 20% of the exterior foundation wall area must be insulated.  It is recommended that you take work-in-progress photos to document retrofits that cannot be visually verified by the energy advisor, such as insulation installed from the outside.</foundation>
                <windows>Through the Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative, grants of either $125 or $250 per window rough opening are available when an ENERGY STAR certified or ENERGY STAR certified Most Efficient window is installed to replace an existing window. Replacing old, damaged or leaky windows with new ENERGY STAR certified products can help you save energy, improve comfort and reduce noise. To determine eligibility of the product you are seeking to purchase, confirm that it is included on the Searchable product list of eligible windows for the Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative.&#x0D;&#x0A; &#x0D;&#x0A;ENERGY STAR labels must be affixed to windows at the time of installation and remain in place until the time of your post-retrofit evaluation. If ENERGY STAR labels are removed prior to the post-retrofit evaluation, the following photos are your responsibility to acquire, retain and provide to the energy advisor at the time of the post-retrofit evaluation:&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;A photo of each newly-installed window showing a portion of the surrounding wall assembly from the &#x0D;&#x0A;inside, outside or both, AND &#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;A photo of each ENERGY STAR label affixed to the window that clearly shows the ENERGY STAR &#x0D;&#x0A;certification mark, Manufacturer model code/number, U-factor/Energy Rating (ER), NRCan reference &#x0D;&#x0A;number or a Certified Products Directory (CPD) number, and a Certified mark from one of the &#x0D;&#x0A;following: &#x0D;&#x0A;- Canadian Standards Association (CSA)&#x0D;&#x0A;-Intertek Canada&#x0D;&#x0A;-Keystone Certifications&#x0D;&#x0A;-Labtest Certification (LC)&#x0D;&#x0A;-QAI Laboratories&#x0D;&#x0A;-National Fenestration Council (NFRC)&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;Removed labels must be provided to the energy advisor.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;Request your supplier/installer to include the following information on the invoice:&#x0D;&#x0A;-Name of the homeowner and address of the house;&#x0D;&#x0A;-Date of installation;&#x0D;&#x0A;-Window make and model numbers;&#x0D;&#x0A;-NRCan Reference Number;&#x0D;&#x0A;-Indication of whether windows are ENERGY STAR or ENERGY STAR Most Efficient certified;&#x0D;&#x0A;-Number of windows and location of each installation;&#x0D;&#x0A;-U-factor/Energy Rating (ER);&#x0D;&#x0A;-Itemized cost of each window and total cost of installation; and&#x0D;&#x0A;-Itemization of any other work done as part of the installation, such as air/gap sealing and associated costs.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;Please note that a window schedule (quote) cannot be used as a substitute for the aforementioned acceptable window validations and cannot be submitted to the portal as a standalone document to validate window installation and eligibility. However, the window schedule may be attached to the invoice provided there is a reference on the invoice to a schedule reference number to link the two documents.</windows>
                <doors>Through the Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative, grants of either $125 or $250 per window rough opening are available when an ENERGY STAR certified or ENERGY STAR certified Most Efficient window is installed to replace an existing window. Replacing old, damaged or leaky windows with new ENERGY STAR certified products can help you save energy, improve comfort and reduce noise. To determine eligibility of the product you are seeking to purchase, confirm that it is included on the Searchable product list of eligible windows for the Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative.&#x0D;&#x0A; &#x0D;&#x0A;ENERGY STAR labels must be affixed to windows at the time of installation and remain in place until the time of your post-retrofit evaluation. If ENERGY STAR labels are removed prior to the post-retrofit evaluation, the following photos are your responsibility to acquire, retain and provide to the energy advisor at the time of the post-retrofit evaluation:&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;A photo of each newly-installed window showing a portion of the surrounding wall assembly from the inside, outside or both, AND &#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;A photo of each ENERGY STAR label affixed to the window that clearly shows the ENERGY STAR certification mark, Manufacturer model code/number, U-factor/Energy Rating (ER), NRCan reference number or a Certified Products Directory (CPD) number, and a Certified mark from one of the following: &#x0D;&#x0A;- Canadian Standards Association (CSA)&#x0D;&#x0A;-Intertek Canada&#x0D;&#x0A;-Keystone Certifications&#x0D;&#x0A;-Labtest Certification (LC)&#x0D;&#x0A;-QAI Laboratories&#x0D;&#x0A;-National Fenestration Council (NFRC)&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;Removed labels must be provided to the energy advisor.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;Request your supplier/installer to include the following information on the invoice:&#x0D;&#x0A;-Name of the homeowner and address of the house;&#x0D;&#x0A;-Date of installation;&#x0D;&#x0A;-Window make and model numbers;&#x0D;&#x0A;-NRCan Reference Number;&#x0D;&#x0A;-Indication of whether windows are ENERGY STAR or ENERGY STAR Most Efficient certified;&#x0D;&#x0A;-Number of windows and location of each installation;&#x0D;&#x0A;-U-factor/Energy Rating (ER);&#x0D;&#x0A;-Itemized cost of each window and total cost of installation; and&#x0D;&#x0A;-Itemization of any other work done as part of the installation, such as air/gap sealing and &#x0D;&#x0A;associated costs.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;Please note that a window schedule (quote) cannot be used as a substitute for the aforementioned &#x0D;&#x0A;acceptable window validations and cannot be submitted to the portal as a standalone document to &#x0D;&#x0A;validate window installation and eligibility. However, the window schedule may be attached to the &#x0D;&#x0A;invoice provided there is a reference on the invoice to a schedule reference number to link the two &#x0D;&#x0A;documents.&#x0D;&#x0A;</doors>
                <HeatingSystem>Through the Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative, a grant between $2,500 and $5,000 is available for installing a new ENERGY STAR certified air source heat pump or cold climate air source heat pump system. The grant amount is based on the type and configuration of the heat pump system: $2,500 is available for mini- or multi-split systems with two indoor head and $5,000 is available for cold climate air source heat pump central systems or mini- or multi-split systems with a minimum of three indoor heads. Speak with a mechanical system contractor/designer for recommendations on the type of heat pump system that is best suited for &#x0D;&#x0A;your home. &#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;Depending upon the region in which you live and how you heat your home today, the installation of a heat pump may result in lower or higher utility costs. Consult with a mechanical system contractor to determine if this type of system is practical and the right choice for your circumstances.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;The Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative requires that the heat pump system is capable of distributing heat throughout the entire conditioned space in the home, including the basement. This applies regardless of whether the heat pump system is a centrally ducted, mini- or multi-split ducted or ductless system. The sizing and selection of the heat pump is to be determined in consultation with the mechanical system contractor and a sizing guide tool, such as the one offered by Natural Resources Canada. &#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;To determine the eligibility of the product you are seeking to purchase, use the AHRI number and make and model of the indoor and outdoor units provided by the mechanical system contractor to &#x0D;&#x0A;confirm that it is included on the Searchable product list of eligible heat pumps for the Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A; - 1) Confirm that it is included on the list of eligible equipment as found on the Canada Greener Homes Grant webpage. See link below&#x0D;&#x0A;https://oee.nrcan.gc.ca/pml-lmp/index.cfm?language_langue=en&amp;action=app.search-recherche&amp;appliance=ASHP1_GH&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A; - 2) For ductless heat pumps, a minimum of 2 indoor heads with 1 head per floor including basements higher than 5' 10"" (finished or unfinished) is required as to supply heat to the entire home. For central systems, a minimum of 2 supply registers per floor ( including basements) are required.&#x0D;&#x0A;For complete guidelines please visit: https://www.nrcan.gc.ca/energy-efficiency/homes/canada-greener-homes-grant/start-your-energy-efficient-retrofits/plan-document-and-complete-your-home-retrofits/eligible-grants-for-my-home-retrofit/23504#s5&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A;For more information: Natural Resources Canada has developed a package of materials related to air source heat pump sizing and selection, intended for use by mechanical system designers and renovation contractors:&#x0D;&#x0A; https://www.nrcan.gc.ca/maps-tools-and-publications/tools/modelling-tools/toolkit-for-air-source-heat-pump-sizing-and-selection/23558&#x0D;&#x0A;</HeatingSystem>
                <Renewables>Through the Canada Greener Homes Grant initiative, $1,000 per kW DC is available for installing a solar photovoltaic (PV) system. If you choose to install a PV system, it is strongly recommended that a full assessment by a professional solar PV installer, including an estimate of solar insolation (how much sunlight falls on the roof) is undertaken to provide detailed information on considerations for your home and specific installation recommendations, including the size and related energy production of the system.  The rated PV panels must have a rated peak power capacity higher than or equal to 1.0 kW DC. The system must be composed of PV panels and an inverter certified to CSA Standards. Solar panels can be mounted on the house or ground, as long as they are on the property / land of the house associated with the application. Building permits may be required for both off-grid and grid-connected installations. For a grid connected system, a copy of the letter of approval or permission for interconnection issued by the local electrical or building authority is required. For more information, refer to Natural Resources Canada’s Solar Ready Guidelines.</Renewables>
                <AdditionalComments>CANADA GREENER HOMES GRANT&#x0D;&#x0A; Through the Canada Greener Homes Grant, homeowners are eligible for up to $600 for the cost of pre- and post-retrofit EnerGuide evaluations and up to $5,000 total for the implementation of eligible retrofits completed after December 1, 2020.&#x0D;&#x0A;Hiring a contractor is the recommended option in undertaking several of the home retrofits and for some retrofits it is a requirement. The contractor is responsible for complying with local bylaws and relevant provincial, territorial and federal legislation and guidelines.&#x0D;&#x0A; ELIGIBILITY INFORMATION&#x0D;&#x0A; For full details on eligibility requirements, eligible measures and grants for the recommended measures outlined below, please consult the Canada Greener Homes Grant website at canada.ca/greener-homes-grant or your Homeowner Information Kit.&#x0D;&#x0A; Many eligible retrofit measures under the Canada Greener Homes Grant have certain conditions for eligibility. These include:&#x0D;&#x0A; 1. In order to be eligible for reimbursement for your retrofit, you must complete at least one retrofit that is both eligible and recommended by an energy advisor in this Renovation Upgrade Report&#x0D;&#x0A; - If you wish to undertake resiliency measures or purchase a thermostat, you must also undertake another eligible energy efficiency measure in order to qualify for a grant.&#x0D;&#x0A; - Purchased equipment such as heat pumps and windows must meet eligibility criteria and must be on the eligible product list as found on the Canada Greener Homes Grant website. This information can also be found in the Homeowner Information Kit&#x0D;&#x0A; - All mechanical and electrical systems, with the exception of thermostats, must be installed by a licensed and trained professional&#x0D;&#x0A; - It is highly recommended that you use the attestation forms found on the Canada Greener Homes Grant website and Canada Greener Homes Grant Portal (if applicable for your retrofit) confirming that:&#x0D;&#x0A; - installation of an electrical or mechanical system has been completed by a trained and licensed professional*&#x0D;&#x0A; - an earth-energy (ground or water) system was installed in accordance with CSA standards&#x0D;&#x0A; - the heat pump has been sized to your entire home&#x0D;&#x0A; *When using a licensed professional it is highly recommended that you obtain proof of their licence to install equipment in your province or territory.&#x0D;&#x0A; - All products must be purchased in Canada. Online purchases are only eligible if they are ordered from an online distributor located in Canada.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A; ADDITIONAL OPPORTUNITIES FOR INCENTIVES&#x0D;&#x0A; You may access and combine grant funding from the Canada Greener Homes Grant with funding from other retrofit grant programs in your region. The sum of the funding you receive from all sources must not exceed 100% of the total cost of the pre- and post-retrofit EnerGuide evaluations and of each eligible retrofit measure.&#x0D;&#x0A; Participants will be required to declare through the Canada Greener Homes Grant Portal funding or rebates received from other sources.&#x0D;&#x0A;&#x0D;&#x0A; ***Proof of primary residence is one of the requirements to participate in the Greener Homes program.&#x0D;&#x0A;</AdditionalComments>
